[Music]
the stoa
is a digital campfire where we cohere in
dialogue
about what matters most at the knife's
edge of what's happening now
estoa is a digital campfire where we
gather and cohere
at the knife's edge of this moment
and today we are joined by lawrence
curry clark
lcc in the room and he is going to
invite us into a game glass bead game
so lcc welcome to the stoa thank you for
being here i'll also mention this was
advertised as
60 minutes um but
we will stay likely up to 90. so
if you want to stick around for a bit
longer you are free to do so
get in more games all right lcc welcome
to the stowa
thank you tyson welcome everybody
every mind and every soul to the
glassbeat game
before we do anything at all i would
like to
invite you to do a bit of d-matrixing
we're going to break out of the trance
that we bring
into this space we're going to shake it
free from our body
and we're going to prepare to spin
ourselves a new trance
so i'd like to invite everybody to stand
up
to let their body shake to shake out all
the tension in their body
especially let out the tension inside of
your jaw
we're going to be talking tonight we're
going to be playing with the tongue so
let that jaw loose
and don't be afraid to speak in tongues
let your tongue
speak its own language
shake it all out shake out all the day
shake out this whole year of 2020.
shake out the last decades of your life
until there's nothing left
[Music]
ah
thank you everybody for joining me in
that
switch that spin
breaking out into a new space
i now invite everybody to join in
a brief meditation make yourself
comfortable
slow down your breath
empty the mind
return to nothingness
and keeping your eyes closed
allow me to explain
the framework of the grasping game
or better said the play frame
a civilization 150
generations old
found itself on the cusp
of a techno cambrian explosion
it was called to shape this great
wave of evolution
but soon they realized
that they had been dispossessed of their
law
of their idols of their language
of their icons
and that they were caught in a trance
spun
long ago that wouldn't stop spinning how
were they going to break
this old trance and start spinning a new
one
how could they start spinning a new turn
that would save them
from a potential dystopia
and lead them they hoped
towards the utopia the good place
their method would be to reclaim
their symbolic territory
to reclaim their language to reclaim
their icons to reclaim their idols
and give birth to a new newest sphere
that would nourish them all
thank you everybody for your attention
and welcome to the glassbeat game
today we're going to be co-creating
the truth process by cultivating our
individual perspectives and exploring
their synergies
the glassbeat game in its most basic
form
is played between two players
each taking one minute turns
to explore a specific topic
and trying to interconnect as much as
possible
during the conversation to try and
generate from the
individual perspectives a synergy
the topics that we
play with serve
as portals into the newest sphere
they try and represent fundamental
concepts
that
serve as a portal into the whole
interconnected
web of ideas by
entering into any portal one enters into
all portals simultaneously
but the topic serves as an anchor for
each game so the two players
use that as a starting point
to explore their own perspective
and the space in between their
perspectives
there's only one rule really which is to
take
turns
but there are ideals to the game
the first ideal is that
we avoid the use of i
and you to bypass the ego
enter into the collective intelligence
and tap into the distributed
consciousness
we also try to intertwine
our moves as much as possible with the
other players moves
to try and create as many points of
interconnection
by paying close attention to the other
player
and nourishing the other player with our
attention
so they feel listened to and they feel
called to express
more and more
and finally we try and concentrate
as much of our truth as much of our
perspective
into each of our moves
some tips for play
if you by accident use i or you
which is very common don't worry about
it
just observe it let it flow past
because the most important thing is the
flow
try and speak faster than you can think
let yourself be surprised by the truth
which is inside of you
which you never thought was there
the great temptation of the game
is to start thinking about what you are
going to say
when the other person is speaking
remember to pay attention to the other
nourish the other
with your attention
take in their move in its entirety
and trust yourself that you
have something to say something will
emerge
and finally remember that
sound
is as valuable
as silence
i'm now going to invite tyson
to play a presentation game with me
so everybody can get an idea of the flow
of the game
of how it's played
so for this purpose we're going to be
using
the game timer everybody can find the
game timer
on the website glassbeadgames.com that
michael has just posted
into the chat
and when we go into the breakout rooms
this is what's going to allow you to
synchronize
the games together so everybody's going
to be on the same timer
everybody's going to be playing
simultaneously
so maybe there'll be some kind of weird
synchronicities going on
or maybe not but for now
seeing that only tyson and myself are
going to be playing
we're going to
connect to glasbygames.com
we're going to go to timer
and the first the reference for the
first
game
is initiation so you'll see there's
a timer reference where you type in
initiation and you click
click join
is that working for you time for you
tyson yep
i pressed join and now i see initiation
game duration will be 11 minutes game
inactive
okay great
just tell me when you want to go around
thank you jen
so before the game we begin
with a one minute meditation to empty
the mind remember resist the temptation
to think about what
we're going to say tyson i shall do my
best to do the same
and i invite everybody to join us inside
of this
meditative space and then we're going to
play
10 minute game five turns each
and we'll see where it takes us
so jen
please laura do you want me to drop the
topic in at the end of the meditation
ah yes please eric you you know the
topic
so we don't know the topic right now
um but at the end of the meditation eric
will drop the topic in
and i will begin if that's all right
with you tyson
okay here we go jen take us away
topic is truth truth
the synergy of all perspectives
the synergy of all perspectives be they
human
and otherwise learning to listen to the
truth of the earth
learning to listen to the truth of the
moon learning to listen to the truth of
the stars of the dark matter
of all of the space
learning to listen to the truth of the
in between
learning to clean one's ears
learning to clean one's eyes
learning how to repair broken
spectacles
learning how to stare into the sun and
not get blinded
learning how to hold one's breath
underneath the waves without drowning
cleaning my ears cleaning
the eyes diving into fresh cold
water being cleansed of spiritual gunk
to be more clear
and capable of knowing the truth if it
were seen
if it were if it were present presenting
itself
truth truth
where where does where does the path of
truth lead
pulling my spectacle lens out of my
pocket after it
fell out of my glasses i'm seeing kind
of
strangely now i'm using i
seeking for the true way to play
the true way to be here with others
staring at the sun
seeking the connection with all of the
dimensions
of being and mixing them blending
them together separating them into their
different
ways and then recombining them into that
white light every color
every frequency
the verticality climbing up the mountain
and touching the depths
of the oceans wearing strange glasses
wearing a monocle
spending a day with one eye closed
purifying the self so that the truth may
enter
emptying the vessel
being too full to be able to drink
another sip
regurgitation
get it out get it out distractions
self-imposed limitations
little chips of dust on the spectacles
cracks let me just stomp on these right
now
he'll heal the sight heal the vision
heal the eyes
heal the ears truth is here
what is being found what is being found
what wants to happen
out of our own way out of my own way
she's out of her own way
we're all out of the way
fusion fusion two eyes
so that i can see your perspective
so that i can see
finding the truth when one is not
looking for it
stumbling over what one thought was a
great stone but was actually just a tiny
little
condensed pill of truth
a truth sibo pill so
potent that if one was to swallow it it
would explode one's mind
learning how to swallow
learning how to digest
learning how to breathe
breathing onto a mirror which is so
close to one's face
it becomes all smoky and one can't even
see oneself
smashing the mirror placing it onto a
sphere
spinning the sphere looking into all of
the different reflections
looking into all the different
reflections
looking through strange glass windows
looking to the bottom of the well
don't dirty the well
fish watching very closely
swimming just keep swimming
ah thinking
thinking overthinking overthinking
wondering projecting onto the
perspective of other people what it is
that they're thinking
unthinking not thinking being looking
back into the well now
trapped at the bottom of a well
that has been poisoned
that never stops vibrating one can never
find the stillness
trapped at the bottom of a well
whose walls are made of mirrors
infinite reflection
can't make any sense
every time one moves
the water ripples can never become still
and it can never repair
the poison still
grows it will thicken
more and more more and more
thickens more and more like the sound of
the microphone as it changed
thickens more and more like the density
of thought
working to make sense and come to truth
the water's getting thicker it's moving
slower it's viscous
i'm swimming in maple syrup
silliness humor play unknowingness
something
waiting for something to happen waiting
for something great to happen
maybe it can spark a smile maybe
joy will be felt it'll ripple miles
waiting waiting waiting
doing doing frantically doing searching
running rushing
left turn right turn
things are moving quickly now velocity
switching unknown mystery embarrassment
embarrassed by one's incapability
to tell the truth always
caught in a great wave of lies that
began before
our birth through
us lies continue to flow
through us truth continues to flow
if we can tap into those past waves we
can keep
those waves crashing
onto the saw
crashing onto the
shores of the mind
paying attention to
the lies that we are being fed
learning to shape those waves
to shape those symbols
to project
saying what is meant meaning what is
said
moving slowly with patience discernment
quickly in the moment knowing boom
shift deflect redirect dodge
connect here now what's going
on checking it out checking it out
shining a flashlight
hearing a sound look over there bounce
move quick
fast slow uh i want the truth
truth is wanted something that is felt
not
comfort from safety but a knowingness a
hereness
a belonging to the land
something that is being done together
a pursuit a pursuit now
wonder curiosity completion
thank you tyson good game
thank you
so i hope that gave everybody an idea of
the the space inside which uh
there is to play uh we're now going to
break out into rooms of two and
everybody's gonna get an opportunity to
play the game i invite you all to
go to glasbygames.com if you haven't
already
and click on the timer and
when asked for the reference type in
initiation
you'll then have um
a few minutes to get ready
and after a few minutes we'll press play
on the timer all the timers will run
simultaneously
and there'll be a one minute meditation
you will have 10 total turns 5 each
choose who is going to begin before you
start
and the topic will be truth